I never expected...
(山崎)まさか 伊東のﾔﾂ…
ﾔﾂらと手を結んでいたなんて｡
Ito to be allied with them...
I need to tell the Vice-Chief immediately.
副長に… 早く！ 副長に…！
The Vice-Chief!
(土方)頼む…｡
Please...
真選組を…
ｵﾚの… ｵﾚたちの真選組を…➡
The Shinsengumi... My...
Our Shinsengumi...
護って… くれ…｡
Protect it.
Please...
(伊東)近藤さん… すまないね｡
Kondo-san, I'm sorry.
ｷﾐたちの御旗は➡
Your flag has become pitch black.
もう真っ黒に
なってしまったんだよ｡
(近藤)ｸｸｸ… わ～はっはっは!!
さすが先生
おもしろいことを言うなぁ！
As expected, Sensei...
You say interesting things.
ｵﾚたちが 真っ黒に染まった？
We've become pitch black?
先生のまわりにいる連中は
知らんが ﾔﾂらは 違う｡
I don't know about those around you...
But they're different.
They can't be called a color.
ﾔﾂらは 色なんて呼べる
代物じゃねえ｡
If anything, they're grime.
言ってみりゃあ 垢だよ｡
They're stains that you can't remove,
no matter how much you wash.
洗ってもとれねえ
染みついちまった汚れだ｡
They can't be colored or
affected by anything.
ﾔﾂらは 何色にも
塗り潰せないし➡
何ものにも 染まらん｡
Okita-kun, what are you doing?
You're supposed to be keeping watch.
(伊東)沖田君 何をやっている？
ｷﾐは 見張りのはず…｡
(沖田)ﾃﾒｴは 何やってんだ？
What are you doing?
(沖田)ﾃﾒｴが何やってんだって
聞いてんだ ｸｿ野郎｡
I'm asking you what you're
doing, you piece of shit.
(隊士)沖田君！
伊東先生に なんて口を！
Okita-kun...
How dare you talk like that to Ito Sensei?!
手を離せ｡
うわ!?
Let go.
I said, let go of him!!
その人から
手を離せって言ってんだ！
[Ito's faction plans to assassinate Kondo. Upon discovering
this plan, Gintoki and the others chase after the train.]
[Hijikata has become a hopeless otaku.
Is there any way to save Kondo?]
["There's a Thin Line Between
Strengths and Weaknesses"]
♪♪～
総悟…｡
Sogo...
Okita-kun, so you really were
part of Hijikata's faction.
(伊東)沖田君…
やはり ｷﾐは 土方派…｡
You were a spy who got close to me
to find out what I was going to do.
ﾎﾞｸに近づき
その動向を探るための ｽﾊﾟｲ…｡
土方を裏切ったのも
ﾎﾞｸを欺くための芝居だったか｡
Your betrayal of Hijikata was
all an act to fool me.
…芝居じゃねえよ｡
That wasn't an act.
I told you... All I want is to be Vice-Chief.
I'll crush anyone who gets in my way.
(沖田)言ったはずだ…
ｵﾚの眼中にあるのは➡
副長の座だけだ｡
ｼﾞｬﾏなﾔﾂは 誰だろうと 叩き潰す｡
土方は 消えた｡
Hijikata disappeared... You're next, Ito Sensei.
次は ﾃﾒｴの番だよ
伊東先生｡
ｵﾚは ﾃﾒｴの下にも ﾔﾂの下にも
つくのは ごめんだ｡
I don't want to work under him
or you. I have only one boss.
ｵﾚの大将は ただ１人｡
そこをどけ！
そこの隣は ｵﾚの席だ！
Out of the way! That spot
by his side is mine!!
ﾊﾊﾊ… とんだ性悪だ｡
How ill-natured. You used
me to get rid of Hijikata.
土方を消すため ﾎﾞｸを利用し
用済みとあらば ﾎﾞｸをも消すか｡
And, now that I'm of no use,
you're going to get rid of me.
いいじゃないか
ﾎﾞｸも ｷﾐと同じ意見だ｡
Why not? I have the same idea as you.
…ﾌｯ｡
ﾌｯ…｡
(２人)うお～！
(みんな)うわ～！
(警報)
(新八)近藤さんが このままじゃ
近藤さんが 暗殺される！
Kondo-san!! At this rate, Kondo-san
will be assassinated!!
(土方)ﾎﾞｸは 知らない…｡
ﾎﾞｸは 知らない…｡
It's none of my concern...
ﾊﾊ… ﾎﾞｸは知らない…｡
土方さん しっかりしてください
土方さん！
Hijikata-san!! Get a hold
of yourself, Hijikata-san!!
ﾎﾞｸ 知らないもん 知らないもん…｡
It's none of my concern...
It's of no concern...
このままじゃ あなたの大切な人が
大切なものが…｡
At this rate, you may lose all
the people and things...
You hold dear!!
全部 なくなっちゃうかも
しれないんですよ！
…知らないもん
ﾎﾞｸ 知らない…｡
It's of no concern... It's
none of my concern...
Gin-chan, what should we do?
(神楽)銀ちゃん どうするｱﾙ？
((土方:ｵﾚたちの… 真選組を
護ってくれ…))
Please protect...
Our Shinsengumi...
Kagura, patch us through to
headquarters and all cars.
(銀時)神楽 無線で
全車両から本部までつなげろ！
(神楽)あいあいさ！
Aye, aye, sir.
[無線]あ～ もしもし
聞こえますか？ 税金泥棒｡
Umm... Hello? Can you hear
me you tax thieves?
伊東派だか
ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞ派だか知らねえが➡
I'm not sure if it's the Ito faction
or the Mayonnaise faction...
But I'm saying this to
all of you tax thieves!
すべての税金泥棒どもに告ぐ！
Immediately leave your posts and
go after the train that Kondo's on.
今すぐ持ち場を離れ
近藤の乗った列車を追え！
If you waste time, your boss...
もたもたしてたら
ﾃﾒｴらの大将 首とられちゃうよ！
Might be killed.
This is an order. Those
who ignore this order...
ｺｲﾂは命令だ！ そむいたﾔﾂには➡
士道不覚悟で
切腹してもらいま～す！
Will have to commit seppuku for
not standing by their bushido.
[無線]ｲﾀｽﾞﾗか？ ﾃﾒｴ誰だ！
Is this a prank?! Who are you?!
Who do you think you're
talking to? Who am I?
ﾃﾒｴこそ
誰に口きいてんだ！ 誰だと？
真選組 副長！
土方 十四郎だ ｺﾉﾔﾛｳ！
This is Shinsengumi Vice-Chief
Toshiro Hijikata, damn it!!
ﾌﾝ！
銀さん？
Humph!
Gin-san...
I'm sick of seeing that cowardly face.
ふぬけたﾂﾗは 見飽きたぜ｡
ちょうどいい｡
真選組が消えるなら➡
This is convenient.
If the Shinsengumi is going to disappear,
you can disappear with them.
ﾃﾒｴも一緒に消えればいい｡
I'll send you to your grave.
墓場までは送ってやらぁ｡
冗談じゃない！
No way! I'm not going!
ﾎﾞｸは行かない！
ﾃﾒｴに言ってねえんだよ！
I wasn't talking to you!!
うわ～っ！
Hey, are you listening? Are you?
おい 聞いてるかｺﾗ あん？
Don't retreat and shove your
problems onto other people!!
勝手にｹﾂまくって 人様に厄介事
押しつけてんじゃねえぞ ｺﾗ！
Are you the type that asks
things of others?
ﾃﾒｴが 人にものを頼むﾀﾏか？
Are you the type that
ﾃﾒｴが真選組
他人に押しつけて くたばるﾀﾏか？
shoves the fate of your Shinsengumi
onto someone else?
くたばるんなら
大事なもんの傍らで➡
If you're going to die,
die while swinging your sword along side
the things that are important to you!!
剣振り回してくたばりやがれ！
それが ﾃﾒｴだろうが！
That's who you are!!
ってえなぁ…｡
いてえって言ってんだろ～が！
That hurts...
I told you, that hurts!!
うわ～っ！
ﾊｧ ﾊｧ…｡
あっ まさか… まさか！
Could it be?
Could it be?!
(篠原)伊東先生！ 爆破か所から
炎が出て これ以上は危険です！
Ito Sensei, the train is on fire! It's
dangerous for us to stay here!
列車を止めるな！
止めれば 近藤に逃げられる｡
Don't stop the train!! If we
stop, Kondo will escape.
(伊東)この列車には
あの２人以外➡
Everyone on this train aside from
those two are our allies.
我々の仲間しかいない｡
列車が走り続ける限り➡
As long as this train continues
moving, they're trapped like rats.
ﾔﾂらは 袋のﾈｽﾞﾐだ！
(近藤)すまねえ 総悟｡
Sorry, Sogo. It's all my
fault this happened.
こんなことになったのは
すべて ｵﾚ１人のせいだ｡
なんてわびればいい…｡
How can I make it up
to you? How can I...
ｵﾚは お前らに
ﾄｼに… なんてわびればいい？
apologize to you...to Toshi?
How can I apologize?
(近藤)総悟！
Sogo!!
何をやっている 総悟！
What are you doing, Sogo?! Open up!!
開けろ！
Kondo-san...
(沖田)近藤さん｡
大将の首とられたら 戦は負けだ｡
If our boss is killed, we'll lose this battle.
ここは引き下がっておくんなせえ｡
ふざけるな！
Please stay here.
No way!!
くぅ…｡
Kondo-san, I've constantly told you
(沖田)近藤さん
だから何度も言ったでしょ｡
ｱﾝﾀの悪いところは
人がよすぎるところだって｡
that the bad thing about you is
that you're too good a person.
誰でも信じて 疑おうとしねえ｡
You believe anyone and
never doubt them.
In the end, a fox like him
ended up by your side.
(沖田)挙げ句 あのｷﾂﾈまで
懐に抱え込んじまうたぁ｡
Well, I expected this would
happen sooner or later.
まぁ いつかは
こうなると思ってやしたがねぇ｡
だが そんなｱﾝﾀだからこそ
ｵﾚたちゃ集まったんだ｡
But because you're like that,
we gathered around you...
(沖田)そんなｱﾝﾀだからこそ
一緒に戦ってきたんだ｡
Because you're like that,
we fought with you.
そんな ｱﾝﾀだから
命張って護るかいがあるのさ｡
Because you're like that...
You're worth risking my life to protect.
くぅ… 総悟待て！
Sogo! Wait!!
ｵﾒｴに死なれたらｵﾚは ｵﾚは…｡
If you die, I... I...
Sogo!!
総悟！
Okita-kun, I thought you
were smarter than that.
沖田君 ｷﾐはもっと
利口な男だと思っていたが…｡
我々全員を
１人で片づけるつもりか？
Do you plan to fight us all by yourself?
You let Kondo escape and remained
behind with the enemy.
(伊東)近藤を逃がし １人 敵陣に
残り 討ち死にすることで➡
Do you plan to die a heroic death?
悲壮美にでも浸ろうというのかね｡
Unfortunately, Kondo is going
to die according to my plans.
だが 残念だったな｡
近藤は ﾎﾞｸの計画どおり 死ぬ｡
(伊東)この戦場にいるのは
ﾎﾞｸたちだけではない｡
We aren't the only ones
on this battlefield.
鬼兵隊か｡
The Kiheitai, huh?
♪♪～
ﾌｯ… わりぃね 伊東さん｡
実は ｵﾚも１人じゃねえ｡
Sorry, Ito-san. Actually,
I'm not alone either.
Impossible... That's...
ﾊﾞｶな！ あれは…｡
This is a raid!!
御用改めである！
ﾃﾒｴら 神妙にお縄につきやがれ！
All of you surrender quietly!!
(伊東)土方!?
Hijikata?!
Why is he here?!
なぜ ﾔﾂがこんな所に!?
ｲﾃｯ！
Can't you act cool for just a little longer?!
ﾃﾒｴ！ 少しの間くらい
かっこつけてられねえのか!?
I can't, I can't! It's impossible
for me! I'm scared!!
ﾑﾘ ﾑﾘ…！ ﾎﾞｸには ﾑﾘだよ｡ 怖い!!
In order to raise the morale of your allies,
仲間の士気を高めるには
副長健在の姿を➡
you need to show them that their
Vice-Chief is still kicking!!
見せつけねえと
ﾀﾞﾒだっつうんだよ！
You've got to be kidding me! You only
reverted back when you hit me?!
ふざけんな!!
人を殴るときだけ 復活して
すぐ 元に戻りやがって!!
Tsk... A bunch of eyesores
have crawled out...
ﾁｯ！ 目障りなのが ｿﾞﾛｿﾞﾛと…｡
だが ﾔﾂらを潰すには
軍隊 １個あっても たりねえぜ｡
But an army isn't enough
to take them down.
ﾌﾝ！ 土方め…｡
Hijikata...
今さら 来たところで 何ができる｡
What can he do by showing up now?
I'll wipe them all out, including Kondo.
近藤もろとも
全員 消してくれる｡
ﾌｯ… 消えるのは ﾃﾒｴらだ｡
You're the ones who are
going to get wiped out.
I see some faces I know.
見知った顔も見えるが
そっちについたからにゃ➡
I hope you're prepared to
die for joining that side.
死ぬ覚悟はできてんだろうな？
Shinsengumi Regulation Article 21...
(沖田)真選組 局中法度 第21条｡
敵と内通せし者 これを罰する｡
Those who have been secretly conspiring
with the enemy shall be punished!
ﾃﾒｴら 全員 ｵﾚが粛清する｡
I'll take down all of you.
(伊東)ﾊﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
Don't you see the situation you're in?
自分の状況が見えてないのか？
Here, I'm the faction in power.
今 この場において 主流派は ﾎﾞｸ｡
You're the rebel.
(伊東)反乱分子は
ｷﾐ以外の何者でもない｡
The laws that he created have
no meaning anymore.
ﾔﾂが作った掟など
もはや 何の意味もなさん｡
Your Shinsengumi will disappear.
ｷﾐたちの真選組は消えるのだ｡
(伊東)ﾔﾂを粛清しろ｡
(隊士)はっ！
Get rid of him.
Yes!
As the First Squad Captain
of the Shinsengumi,
真選組 一番隊隊長として ﾃﾒｴらに
最後の教えを授けてやらぁ｡
I shall give you your final lesson.
(沖田)圧倒的に力の差がある敵を
前にしたとき➡
When faced with an enemy who
is considerably more powerful,
it is best to overcome that power
with sheer numbers.
その実力差を覆すには
数に頼るのが いちばんだ｡
呼吸を合わせろ｡
Synchronize your breathing.
Build up spirit in your heart and body.
(沖田)心体ともに気を練り
もっとも充実した瞬間…｡
When you are at your peak...
一斉に斬りかかれ!!
Attack all at once!!
(隊士たち)やぁ～っ!!
そして…！
And...!!
Die.
死んじまいな｡
Are those Anti-Foreigner
Faction members?
ﾔﾂら 攘夷志士か？
Jeez... It looks like it wasn't
just an internal squabble.
ったく！ どうやら ことは
内輪揉めだけじゃねえらしいな｡
Kondo-san...
近藤さん！
Where in the world is Kondo-san?!
近藤さんはいったい どこですか!?
あれｱﾙ！
There!
(神楽)離れた位置を走る
あの車両！
That car that's moving
far behind the train!
All the enemies are headed there!
(神楽)敵は み～んな
あそこへ向かっていくね！
うわ～っ！
That's the situation, Mr. Hijikata.
Take care of the rest yourself!!
…だそうだ 土方氏｡
あとは自分で何とかしろ!!
おわっ！
Hey, wait, Mr. Sakata!
(土方)ちょっと待ってよ 坂田氏！
Are you planning to leave me here?!
こんなところに 拙者１人
置いてくつもりか～!?
それは さながら ﾅﾒｯｸ星に
ﾔﾑﾁｬ氏を１人送り込み➡
That's as reckless as sending Mr. Yamcha
to Planet Namek by himself.
[Note: Parody of Dragon Ball. Yamcha
is thought of as the weakest character.]
宇宙の命運を
託すがごとき暴挙だよ～!!
And leaving him to decide
the fate of the universe!!
大丈夫だ｡ お前は
ﾍﾞｼﾞｰﾀだ｡ やれば できる！
It's all right! You're Vegeta!!
You can do it if you try!
[Note: Parody of Dragon Ball. Vegeta
is one of the strong characters.]
坂田氏！
ﾌﾝｯ！
ｵﾜｯ！ ｳﾜｯ！
Mr. Sakata!!
Vice-Chief!!
(原田)副長！
(ｻｲﾚﾝ)
It's the Vice-Chief!
(原田)副長だ！
副長が無事だったぞ!!
The Vice-Chief is all right!!
無事じゃねえだろ！
これ どう見ても！
No matter how you look
at this, I'm not all right!!
ﾌﾝ！ ようやく来やがったか｡
もう お守りは たくさんだ｡
So you've finally come.
I was getting sick of taking care
of him. Take him already.
さっさと ｺｲﾂを引き取ってくんな｡
さんざん迷惑かけたんだ｡
He's caused us a lot of trouble.
ｷﾞｬﾗの方は 幕府から
この口座に入れとけ！
Have the shogunate transfer the
reward into my bank account.
伊東の野郎！
ついに本性を現しやがったか！
Ito, that bastard, has finally
shown his true self!!
おい！ 聞いてる？
だが 副長が戻ってきたからには➡
But we're all right now that
the Vice-Chief is back!!
Hey, are you listening? Transfer my
reward into my bank account...
もう大丈夫だぜ！ みんな！
あの この口座に…｡
副長！ 敵は ｵﾚたちが相手します｡
Vice-Chief, we shall confront the enemy.
You save the Chief in the meantime.
副長は その隙に
局長を救い出してください！
行くぞ!!
Let's go!!
Hey, wait!!
おい 待て！
Hey, wait, damn it!
おい 待て！ この野郎！
Something weird has happened
to your Vice-Chief.
ｵﾒｴらの副長 おかしなことに
なってんだよ！ 聞け ﾊｹﾞ！
Listen to me, baldy!!
♪♪～
ｳﾜｱｧｯ！
ｱｲﾂら なんで…｡
Those guys... Why?
Why?!
なんで…!? あっ…｡
(近藤)ﾊﾞ… ｶ野郎…
なんで お前が➡
You idiot... Why are you...
なんで お前が…
こんなところにいるんだよ…！
Why are you here?
ｵﾚに あんな仕打ちを
受けたお前が➡
I treated you so badly.
ｵﾚのために なんで
こんなところまで…｡
Why did you come all this way for me?
ｸｯ…｡
ﾄｼ～!! なんで来やがった！
Toshi!
Why did you come?
うっ… ﾊﾞｶ野郎！
You idiot!
(近藤)えっ？
Huh?
近藤さ～ん 無事ですかい？
Kondo-san, are you all right?
It's no good. He's not here.
(神楽)ﾀﾞﾒね｡ いないｱﾙ｡
(近藤)何すんだ ﾃﾒｴら！
What the hell do you think you're doing?!
あっ いた｡ 無事か？ おい｡
Oh, there he is! Are you all right?
Hey, it seems that people are really
trying to assassinate you.
なんか お前 暗殺されそうに
なってるらしいな？ 一丁前に｡
(近藤)いや！ 今
されそうになったよ！ たった今！
No, I was almost killed by you just now!!
まさか… お前ら
ﾄｼを ここまで…｡
Could it be that you dragged
Toshi all the way here?
This is impossible. You help us?
ありえなくね？
お前らが ｵﾚたちを…｡
遺言でな… ｺｲﾂの｡
(近藤)遺言？
It was his last request.
His last request?
His soul was devoured
by a demonic sword.
妖刀に 魂 食われちまった｡
Right now, he's just a hopeless otaku.
今のｺｲﾂは ただのﾍﾀれたｵﾀｸ｡
もう戻ってくることもあるめぇ｡
He won't return ever again.
妖刀だと？
A demonic sword?
((近藤:ﾄｼ！
Toshi?!
(ﾄﾓｴ)美少女侍 ﾄﾓｴ5000 見参！
Pretty Samurai Tomoe 5000 is here!
しまった～!!))
Damn it!!
(近藤)ここ最近の
ﾄｼの不可解な行動…｡
If all of Toshi's unexplainable actions were
the result of the demonic sword...
あれが
妖刀のせいだとするならば…｡
((『To LOVEる』って
超おもしろいよね))
To Love-Ru is really great, isn't it?
While in that state, what
did Toshi ask you to do?
そんな状態で ﾄｼが
お前らに何を頼んだんだ！
真選組を護ってくれってよ｡
He asked us to protect the Shinsengumi.
面倒だから ﾃﾒｴでやれって
ここまで連れてきた次第さ｡
It would be a pain to do that, so I brought
him here and told him to do it himself.
Our job ends here. I want you
to transfer the reward to me.
ｵﾚたちの仕事は ここまでだ｡
ｷﾞｬﾗは ﾃﾒｴに振り込んでもらうぜ｡
振り込むさ… ｵﾚの貯金全部…｡
I will... I'll give you all of my savings...
But, Odd Jobs, I have a request for you.
だが 万事屋｡
ｵﾚも お前たちに依頼がある｡
ﾌﾝ… これも
遺言と思ってくれていい｡
Consider this a last request as well.
Take Toshi and run away.
ﾄｼ連れて このまま逃げてくれ｡
(近藤)こんなことに
なったのは ｵﾚの責任だ｡
It's my fault this happened.
戦いを拒む
今のﾄｼを巻き込みたくねえ｡
I don't want Toshi to get involved
in this battle in his current state.
ｵﾚは 伊東に注意しろという
ﾄｼの助言を拒んだ｡
I ignored Toshi's advice to be wary of Ito.
さらには ささいな失態を犯した
ﾄｼを 伊東の言うがまま処断した｡
Furthermore, I punished Toshi for
a petty blunder on Ito's advice.
ｺｲﾂが そんなことに
なってるのも知らずに…｡
I never even knew that this
was happening to him.
ｺｲﾂが そんな身になってまで➡
I didn't know that he was trying to protect
the Shinsengumi, even in his condition.
真選組 護ろうとしてたのも
知らずに…｡
(近藤)ﾌﾟﾗｲﾄﾞの高ぇ ｺｲﾂが
お前らに頭を下げて…➡
I didn't know that, despite his
pride, he lowered his head...
真選組を託したのも知らずに…｡
And entrusted the Shinsengumi to you.
すまなかったな ﾄｼ…｡
すまなかったな みんな…｡
I'm sorry, Toshi... I'm sorry, everyone...
ｵﾚは… ｵﾚは… 大ﾊﾞｶ野郎だ｡
I...I'm...a big idiot...
Tell all the cars to immediately
leave the battlefront.
(近藤)全車両に告げてくれ｡
今すぐ戦線を離脱しろと｡
近藤 勲は 戦死した｡
Isao Kondo has died in battle.
I don't want my friends to fight
each other any more.
これ以上 仲間同士で
やり合うのは たくさんだ…｡
Gentlemen of the Yamato,
our Chief, Isao Kondo...
[Note: Spoof of the Space Battleship Yamato anime series.]
(土方)あ～ あ～ ﾔﾏﾄの諸君｡
我らが局長 近藤 勲は
無事 救出した｡
has been safely rescued.
Victory is within our grasp!
勝機は 我らの手にあり！
局長の顔に泥を塗り
受けた恩を仇で返す 不逞の輩｡
We shall get revenge on
that lawless bunch for besmirching
our Chief's name. Let me say this.
[Note: Spoof of GUNDAM series anime.]
あえて言おう… ｶｽであると！
They are all scum!
今こそ ﾔﾂらを
月に代わって お仕置きするのだ！
In the name of the moon...
[Spoof of Sailor Moon.]
We will punish them!!
[TEL](隊士)おい 誰だ!?
気の抜けた演説してるﾔﾂは？
Hey, who's that? Who's making that silly speech?
Who am I? I'm Shinsengumi Vice-Chief...
誰だと…？
真選組副長 土方 十四郎なりぃ！
Toshiro Hijikata nari!!
[Note: Suffix "Nari" was used by Samurai and by
Korosuke in the Kiteretsu Daihyakka anime.]
土方さん…｡
HIjikata-san...
Mr. Kondo, we shall protect your life.
近藤氏 ﾎﾞｸらは ｷﾐに命を預ける｡
In return, you have an obligation to fulfill.
その代わりに
ｷﾐに課せられた義務がある｡
それは死なねえことだ！
To not die.
Do whatever it takes to live.
何が何でも生き残れ｡
どんなに恥辱にまみれようが➡
No matter how humiliating it may be...
No matter how many squad members
die before your eyes, you must live!
目の前で どれだけ
隊士が死んでいこうが➡
ｷﾐは生きにゃならねえ！
(爆発音)
As long as you're here,
(土方)ｷﾐがいる限り
真選組は終わらないからだ！
the Shinsengumi is not finished.
We joined the Shinsengumi because
we wanted to be with you...
ﾎﾞｸたちは ｱﾝﾀに惚れて
真選組に入ったからだ！
ﾊﾞｶのくせに
難しいこと考えてんじゃねえよ！
You're an idiot.
Don't think about such difficult things!
You should live the way you want to live.
(土方)ﾃﾒｴは ﾃﾒｴらしく
生きてりゃいいんだ！
We just have to protect
you from everyone.
(土方)ｵﾚたちは
何者からも ｿｲﾂを護るだけだ｡
近藤さん…｡
Kondo-san...
ｱﾝﾀは真選組の魂だ｡
You are the soul of the Shinsengumi.
ｵﾚたちは それを護る剣なんだよ｡
We are the sword that protects you.
ﾄｼ…｡
Toshi...
(伊東)一度 折れたｷﾐに
何が護れるというのだ？
You broke once before.
What can you protect?
Hijikata-kun, it seems we have
to settle things between us.
土方君 ｷﾐとは どうあっても
決着をつけねばならぬらしい！
剣なら ここにあるぜ…
よく斬れるやつがよぉ！
I have a sword right here.
One that cuts very well.
♪♪～
Odd Jobs, I heard your rotten sermon!
万事屋！
聞こえたぜ ﾃﾒｴの腐れ説教！
What is it?
なんだい？
(土方)偉そうに
ﾍﾞﾗﾍﾞﾗﾍﾞﾗﾍﾞﾗ語りやがって！
Don't talk as if you're so high and mighty.
ぬうっ…！
Draw it already!
さっさと抜きやがれ｡
(土方)黙りやがれ！
Shut up!
ぬぅ… ﾃﾒｴにひと言 言っておく！
I have one more thing to say to you.
ううっ… くぅっ！
ありがとよぉぉ！
Thank you!!
Hey, hey, it looks like the demonic
sword devoured him again...
おいおい また妖刀に
のまれちまったらしいな｡
ﾄｯｼｰか？ ﾄｯｼｰなのか？
Toshi? Is that Toshi?
ｵﾚは…➡
I'm...
真選組副長 土方 十四郎だぁ！
Shinsengumi Vice-Chief
Toshiro Hijikata!!
[To be continued]
[Preview]
It changed... The rhythm of that
man's soul has changed.
It went from a childish anime song
to a sturdy rock-and-roll tune.
I guess the same goes
for you, too, Ito-dono.
["Important Things Are Hard To See"]
[Hijikata fought off the demonic sword's curse
by himself. He goes to fight Ito one-on-one.]
[Meanwhile, Gintoki is in a fateful confrontation
with Bansai Kawakami.]
[See you next time.]